Julien Zamor

Engineering Manager Tech lead **Solution Architect**

Born 1985-07-16

Address 127 avenue Gambetta

75020 Paris +33.6.37.29.72.80

Email julienzamor@gmail.com

Web Personal page LinkedIn LinkedIn Profile

GitHub @smwhr

About Me

For twenty years I've helped build the internet as much as it helped build me, always with ethical perspective and the desire to make more of the real world.

With an academic background in mathematics and raised by my family in the love of the humanities, I always strive in work environment where the combined hard skills of a team serve culture.

Strong points

Excellent relational skills and empathetic co-worker / manager.

A down-to-earth approach in the (technical) decision making process built on years of experiences of failures and successes geared towards continuous value delivery.

Excellent communication skills (written & spoken) with a focus on fostering knowledge-sharing and encouraging collaboration.

Curious and avid learner of all things old and new.

Skills

Phone

Programming languages

Python – Javascript / Typescript / React – PHP – Swift – Objective-C – Shell - Haskell

Database and query language

Data Engineering (10y+) -Snowflake/Iceberg - dbt parquet/arrow - PostgreSQL/MySQL - ElasticSearch - GraphQL -Databricks - Redis - CouchDB -Neo4J

Infrastructure & Architecture

Product/Solution Architect – DevOps Methodology-AWS-GCP-Docker - Kubernetes - Linux sysadmin - Security & Conformance (ISO27001)

Other tech skills

Knowledge management / Documentation - Notion / Slite / Confluence – Tech Roadmap & Vision - Jira / Asana / Monday -Narrative design tools (twine / ink / inform) - Open Source contributor -FFMPEG/Video

Management skills

Agile Delivery (10y+) – Team lead & management (13y+) - Education and mentoring (10y+) - Tech Sales & Marketing (7y+) – Change management (7y+)

Human languages

French (Native) - English (Fluent)

Experiences

RATP Dev (CITiO)

CTO / Head of Data-Products Engineering

- Supervision and management of development teams (3 products, 4 teams, 20-25 contributors)
- Building of a new data-heavy strategic product in a financially constrained environment
- Change management towards agile/product methodologies
- Oversight of architecture, development, devops, security and run with a hands-on approach
- Product expertise and company-wide tech evangelisation
- Talent acquisition & retention (including in M&A context)
- Contributor to the company-wide strategic technological vision & roadmap
- International context (Europe / MENA / Australia)

#LEAN #SCRUM #Agile #python #snowflake #flink #AWS #R&D #Data Science #Data Analysis #Data Engineering # Data Architecture # Data Modeling # Real time # Product building # Continuous integration/delivery # Change management # Tech roadmap & debt management # Project-wide budgeting # Management mentoring # Tech evangelisation #LeSS Facilitator

Engineering Manager & Tech Lead CITiO

- Engineering manager of a team of 4 engineers (3 front, 1 backend)

- Build & Run of the Transport Analytics product
- Achieved launch of 2 spin off products
- CTO (Founder) advisory in structuring team cooperations
- Tech debt cartography and reduction

React / Typescript # D3js # Datavizualisation # Python # Django # pandas # Data architecture # Application architecture # GCP # Product Management # Team budgeting # Tech mentoring # Team OKRs # Tech Sales & Marketing

CTO (Founder)

Trois Yaourts

November 2013 - February 2021

March 2021 - January 2023

February 2023 - Now

- Successful delivery of more than 50 projects, including some large-scale and complex ones, over a large field of web and mobile technologies with a team of 4
- Conception and delivery of data-oriented product and solutions (Finance Ministry, Paris, local
- Building and maintenance of large-scale business management product (RFID chip impression, stock & supply-chain management, ticketing and control of access, networked sensors & IoT, ...)
- Conception, building and integration of tools for the cinema industry all along the production chain (online streaming, marketing, theater, servicing, production, shooting, ...)
- Technical counseling and external CTO for third parties, including code modernization, hiring test, choice of providers
- Transmedia experience production and development (FranceTV, Arte, movie distributors)

PHP # MySQL # PostgreSQL # Data management # Application architecture # AngularJS # Symfony # Python # Django #VueJS #React #ElasticSearch #Kubernetes #Docker #AWS #Azure #Video encoding #Team & Project Management # Accounting # Sales & Marketing

Programmation teacher

Epitech Digital Paris

- Logic & Algorithms 1st, 2nd year
- Industrialization & cloud 2nd, 3rd year
- PHP Object & Architecture 2nd year
- Business project mentoring 2nd, 3rd year

Technical lead - Web platform

My Major Company

January 2012 - October 2013

November 2014 - July 2021

- Technical choices and liaison with third party provider
- Team manager on the maintenance and evolution of the new version (new business model)
- Development and maintenance of critical business modules (payment, credit...)

PHP # MySQL # AngularJS # Symfony 1.4 # Varnish # Java # Mailing # High volume # Payment systems # Scalable Infrastructure

Earlier Experiences

Fullstack web dev/architect

Jiwa (Investisseurs Réunis/Allomusic) January 2011 - December 2011

Fullstack Web developper

Vodkaster.com February 2010 - December 2010

Backend developper

<u>Digiteka</u> September 2008 - January 2010

Research Internship in cryptography

École Nationale Supérieure des Techniques Avancées

Hobbies & extra-skill

- Inveterate cinephile
- Avid sci-fi reader
- Occasional indie game developper and narrative designer (Itch.io profile)
- Father of two (2018, 2020)

Education

M2 Theorical Computer Science

Paris VII - École Normale Supérieure (Ulm) - Paris - Specialisation: Cryptography of multivariate-systems

M1 Pure & applied mathematics

Columbia University, New York City 2006 - 2007

- Major : Algebra & Topology - Minor: Mathematics of finance 2007 - 2008

March 2008 - July 2008